准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
珊迪的乡村圣诞节
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
定格动画制作
定格动画制片人
导演
统筹
监制
客串
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
大家好啊
Howdy, folks
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
大家快来到海滩上跟我放松坐坐
Why don't y'all belly up to the beach
and sit with me a spell?
我有个圣诞篝火故事
I've got a Christmas campfire story
保证你们会想听
I reckon you'll want to hear
这个故事发生在水下
This here tale takes place underwater
就在一座乡间小镇  名叫裤头村
In a one seahorse town called Bikini Bottom
裤头村
这一天是平安夜
Twas the day before Christmas,
大家都在准备迎接圣诞老人
and every boy and girl was ready for Santa
圣诞老人
快来留在这
除了一只忙碌的松鼠
Except one busy squirrel
她在用科学辛苦工作  修修补补
She was using her science to toil and tinker
但她发现这次的实验有点伤脑筋
but she found this experiment a bit of a thinker
加点圣诞装饰亮片应该就行了
A touch of tinsel ought to do the trick
精灵宝宝
Hey, Elf Bob
珊迪老人
Oh, Sandy Claus
找到圣诞装饰亮片了
I found the tinsel
谢谢你今天来当我的小精灵
Thanks for being my little elf today
话说这是用来干什么的
What's this all for, anyway?
这个发明可以变革圣诞节
This invention will revolutionize Christmas
我打算今晚把它展示给全裤头村看
I'm fixing to reveal it to the whole town tonight
这可是我要送给裤头村的大礼
It'll be my gift to Bikini Bottom
恭喜你了  珊迪
Congratulations, Sandy
你又成功了
You've done it again
一点都不对
No, that ain't right
得做得再好一点才行
I gotta do better than that
得再来几样原材料
I'll need a few more ingredients
才可以准时让实验就绪
if I want this to be ready in time
什么声音
What was that?
该不会是
Was that?
不会吧
No
不可能
It can't be
史赖皮  是你发出来的声音吗
Slappy, did you make that noise?
不是  但我做了个新朋友
No, but I did make a new friend
爸  妈
Pa, Ma
蓝迪  罗迪
Randy, Rowdy
萝丝  奶奶
Rosy, Granny?
你好啊  珊迪
Howdy, Sandy
大家好啊
Howdy, y'all
怎么不早说你还邀请了家人
Why didn't you tell me that you'd invited your family
来裤头村过圣诞
to Bikini Bottom for the holidays?
因为本来就没早说  海绵宝宝
'Cause she didn't, SpongeBob
我们这可是德克萨斯惊喜来访
This here's a good old Texas bushwhack visit
虽然得给家庭小艇钻洞才能沉下来
We had to put a few holes in the family row boat
不过能看到我们家珊迪就值得了
but it was worth it to see our little aquatic acorn
对啊  老妹
Yeah, sis
我们大老远从德克萨斯赶来
we came all the way from Texas
就要来陪你这聪明小松鼠一起过圣诞
just to spend Christmas with little old smartytail you
不完全是这样
And not at all
因为蓝迪又在当逃犯了
because Randy's on the lam again
安全了吗
Is the coast clear?
真是的
Well, shoot
早知道你们要过来
If I'd have known y'all were coming
我就去准备烧水了
I would have put the kettle on
救命  小朋友
Help me, kids
快给我缓刑啊
Tag me out
要帮忙吗  珊迪阿姨
You need help, Auntie Sandy?
让他变蓝
Make him turn blue
那是个什么鬼东西
What in the yellow snow was that?
抱歉
Sorry
那个是我的工作闹钟
That was my work alarm
我得去蟹堡王
I got to get to the Krusty Krab
上我一年当中最爱的班  平安夜班
for my favorite shift of the whole year, Christmas Eve
要不我们一起跟过去吧
Why don't we all tag along?
可以啊
We'd just love to
我们可想念深海里的各位朋友了
We have dearly missed all our deep sea buddies
蟹堡王
圣诞快乐  蟹堡王的客人们
Merry Christmas, Krusty customers
圣诞佳节是不是很神奇啊
Aren't the holidays magical?
你肯定是想说悲剧
I think you mean tragical
谁害你这么生气的
Who upchucked in your eggnog?
此处点餐
再唱一遍  章鱼哥先生
Sing it again, Mr. Squidward
还得再多来点圣诞小费呢
We need more Christmas tips
蟹堡王  蟹堡王
Krusty Krab, Krusty Krab
每天都要来这吃
Eat here every day
什么什么蟹黄堡
Something, something, Krabby Patties
别忘了付钱
Don't forget to pay
你烂死了
You stink
蟹老板  干嘛非得要我唱歌
Mr. Krabs, why do I have to sing?
就不能让我改吹竖笛吗
Can't I just play my clarinet instead?
不能就是不能
No can do
我拿它当圣诞柴烧了
I'm using it as a yule log today
五折
什么
What?
你好啊  蟹老板
Howdy, Mr. Krabs
你这边这位唱圣诞颂歌的还真是喜庆
You sure have a festive Christmas caroler there
祝他平安
Bless his heart
谢谢  奇克斯太太
Thank you, Mrs. Cheeks
他倒能再坚持一下  多给我赚点小费
He could stand to bring in a few more tips, though
其实吧
Matter of fact
我自己也算是个歌手
I'm a little something of a chanteuse myself
不然我们帮你奏点乐赚点钱吧
Maybe we could strum up some tips for you, huh?
只要不用给你们付钱就行
As long as I don't have to pay you
海绵宝宝  打灯
SpongeBob, lights, please
来
Well
圣诞佳节给予多多
Christmas is a time for giving
圣诞佳节收获多多
Christmas is a time for getting
圣诞节各种乐事都多多
Christmas is a time for many things
你知道我们爱荡秋千空翻
You know we love trapeze flipping
爬大树  过上乡村生活
Climbing trees and country living
但全都比不上圣诞老人带的礼物
But nothing beats the gifts that Santa brings
圣诞节来得快
Well, Christmas will come
去得也很快
And Christmas will go
但我无法否认自己最爱这一天
But I can't deny it's the day I love the most
万物闪闪发光
Everything's aglowing
圣诞袜也满满当当
When your stocking's overflowing
树下就放着包好的圣诞礼物
And Santa's gifts are wrapped under the tree
圣诞老人把礼物留给你和我
Yeah, Santa left his gifts for you and me
我做梦都想要今年圣诞赚大钱
I'm dreaming of a green Christmas
我做梦都想要今年圣诞节搞砸
And I'm dreaming of a bah humbug
再见  先生
Good day, sir
大家今晚来我家树屋
Come on down to my tree dome tonight
迎接圣诞大惊喜
for a big Christmas surprise
所以老妹  你老说的这个惊喜是什么
So, sis, what exactly is this surprise
you keep going on about?
该不会是要在圣诞节诈骗大伙儿吧
Or are you giving everybody
the old snake oil for Christmas?
这又不是耍诈  蓝迪
This ain't no scam, Randy
先别急
Now, hold your horses
就快完成了
I'm almost finished
只要添加今天新找到的原材料
I'll just add the extra ingredients I collected today
然后看好
And voila
大功告成  而且时间刚刚好
It's finally ready and just in time
我所有朋友今晚都会来
All my friends will be here tonight
我要让他们今年过的圣诞节非同一般
and I want to make this Christmas special for em
我们这次倒可以帮你
I reckon we can help you
给镇上众鱼大开眼界
impress the fins off this town
毕竟我们的专长就是非同一般
After all, special is our specialty
你们是认真的吗
You really mean it?
谢谢大家
Thanks, y'all
来排练圣诞节精彩特技吧
We got a holiday stunt spectacular to rehearse
祝大家圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, y'all
圣诞快乐  珊迪
Merry Christmas, Sandy
话说你叫我们大家过来
Say, did you gather us here
是不是有什么圣诞大惊喜啊
for some kind of big Christmas surprise?
说实话  我还真有呢
As a matter of fact, I did
什么惊喜呢
But whatever could it be?
会不会是
Some kind of
圣诞佳节
装饰品科技
重大进展
圣诞佳节装饰品科技重大进展
breakthrough in holiday decorative technology?
那就来亲眼看看吧
Well, you'll just have to see for yourselves
为大家献上  速成圣诞树
I present to you the instant Christmas tree
只要滴上这几滴圣诞调配液  然后
Just a few drops of this here yuletide concoction, and
大家就能拥有欢乐圣诞节了
A happy holiday is all yours
为了帮我庆祝
And to help me celebrate
我的家人会出演全新精彩特技
my family will perform
their newest stunt spectacular
胡桃夹子舞
Dance of the Nutcrackers
抓到了
Got you
出发
Here we
同时
今晚好累啊
What a night
好在我明天就要连放364天假了
Good thing my 364 day vacation starts tomorrow
来看看
Now, let's see
裤头村
Bikini Bottom
最好的东西都要留到最后
Saving the best for last
回北极再见
See you back at the North Pole
别把我蛋酒喝光了
And don't drink all my eggnog
潜艇雪橇
马戏团表演
A circus show?
这样过圣诞才对嘛  你们这些派对狂
Now, that's the Christmas spirit, you party animals
圣诞老人
Santa
圣诞老人来了
It's Santa
圣诞老人
Santa
好耶  圣诞老人来了
Boy howdy, that there's Santa Claus
应该要让演出的最后一幕
I reckon we ought to make our finale
加倍盛大  给他好看
extra grand for him
祝大家圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, one and all
这棵树马上就会变德克萨斯大小了
Now this will be a Texas-sized tree
没错
You know it
[ Krampus：坎卜斯，反面圣诞老人
此处用作感叹词 ]
完了
Aw, Krampus
天啊
Oh, my
希望他伤得没那么重
I hope he isn't too hurt
圣诞老人
Santa
跟我说话啊  大块头
talk to me, big fella
圣诞奶奶  复活节兔子来看你了
Mrs. Claus, the Easter Bunny is here to see you
这下不好了
That ain't good
拜托  圣诞老人
Come on, Santa
你不知道今天什么日子吗
Don't you know what day it is?
当然知道了
Of course
情人节快乐
Happy Valentine's Day
那个老人家基本上是没指望了
That old elf is one sugarplum shy of a fruitcake
对啊  兄弟
Yeah, bro
这下圣诞老人还怎么给我们送礼物啊
How is Santa gonna deliver our presents now?
他送不了了
He's not
都怪珊迪把她那棵破树种那么高
Sandy knocked him right out of the sky
害他在天上撞了个正着
with her big dumb tree
所以我才不相信树
That's exactly why I don't trust trees
可是没有礼物  圣诞节还有什么意义
But what's the point of having Christmas
without any presents?
咱就是说  你把圣诞节给毁了
You, like, totally ruined Christmas
完了
Oh, no
全都要怪我
This is all my fault
我真对不起
I'm so sorry, y'all
不会有事的  珊迪
It'll be okay, Sandy
起码圣诞老人还很开心
At least Santa's having a good time
你们要去哪啊
Where are you going?
派对才刚要开始呢
The party's just getting started
于是当晚  小镇陷入了寂静
And so the town went quiet that night
居民们一个接一个地熄灯
One by one, they put out their lights
玩也不是  乐也不是
No fun to be had, no joy to be doing
只能呜呜咽咽
Just the soft, sad sounds of gentle boohooing
我本可吃着南瓜派
Oh, I should be eating pumpkin pie
但却让全城都悲哀
But instead I made the whole town cry
我犯了什么过错
What in the world was I doing
圣诞节完全覆没
Now Christmas is ruined
我在圣诞多忧苦
I got the Christmas blues
感觉自己格格不入
I feel like I just don't belong
多希望能够唱出幸福
Wish that I could sing a happy song
只好在这坐立不安
Guess I'll just sit here and stew
不停地哀泣痛哭
And keep aweeping boohoo
我在圣诞多忧苦
I got the Christmas blues
要是能有意外转机
If only some unexpected fortune
能从天而降就好了
would just appear from above
家人
Hey, kin
看我们发现啥了
Look what we found
跟你们说  全都是圣诞老人的礼物
It's all Santa's gifts, I tell you
没错
Sure is
可以留着吗
Can we keep em?
听见没有  珊迪
Did you hear that, Sandy?
有意外转机从天而降了
An unexpected fortune just appeared from above
你先别急  海绵宝宝
Hold your seahorses, SpongeBob
有了礼物也没用
Ain't no use having gifts
圣诞老人现在都送不了礼物呢
if Santa can't deliver them
她说得对  海绵宝宝
She's right, SpongeBob
圣诞老人还在发病
Santa's still indisposed
所以圣诞节一样还是毁了
Meaning Christmas is still ruined
我们也不是第一年没有过圣诞老人了
This ain't the first time we had a year without Santa
我还记得1874年精灵大罢工那会儿
I remember the Great Elf Strike of 1874
那年圣诞  我们整座小镇都很忧苦
Our whole town was real blue that Christmas
但我们还是尽力挺了过去
but we made the most of it
反正没圣诞老人也没关系
No Santa, no problem
我们奇克斯家联手  自己交换礼物
We Cheeks banded together
and exchanged gifts all on our own
奇克斯家族绝不退缩
The family Cheeks ain't quitters
从前不退缩  现在也不会退缩
We weren't then, and we ain't now
奶奶说得对
Granny's right
一起为圣诞老人而战
Let's do this for Santa
划啊划啊划小船
Row, row, row your boat
来顺流而下
Gently down the stream
加油
Come on
你们能行的
You can do it
驾  驾
Giddyap, giddyap
快看
Lookie
天啊
Oh, dear
火箭发射
真漂亮
Looking good
祝你们送彩蛋好运
Good luck delivering those Easter eggs
珊迪来
Now, Sandy
蓝迪来
Now, Randy
罗迪和萝丝来
Now, Rowdy and Rosy
交给妈  交给爸
On Ma, on Pa
交给奶奶  还有
on Granny, and
我
Me
咱们送礼就得来点音乐  振奋精神
I think we need a little
musical motivation to get this job done
来
Well
圣诞佳节给予多多
Christmas is a time for giving
圣诞佳节收获多多
Christmas is a time for getting
圣诞节各种乐事都多多
Christmas is a time for many things
你知道我们爱欢唱颂歌
And you know we like carol singing
四处溜冰  捉捉水母
Skating round and jellyfishing
但全都比不上我们疯狂大家庭
But nothing beats our nutty family
送礼表示我爱着你
Giving gifts means I love you
但是不如来度过好时光
But not like spending time so happily
圣诞佳节
At Christmas time
一切都很好
Everything's fine
因为需要的东西样样全都有
'Cause we got everything we'll ever need
样样全都有
We'll ever need
虽然我们相隔千里
We may be miles apart
但你们知道在我心中
But you know in my heart
我这坚果与家族大树永不分离
This nut don't fall far from the family tree
大家就位  马上出发
Places, y'all, and here we go
蟹堡王
转啊转啊  往右拐弯
Round and round and turn to the right
平安夜来  应该没错
It's Christmas Eve, it should be bright
蟹堡王里  一片荒凉
The Krusty Krab looks mighty low
海绵宝宝  与我共舞
Come on, SpongeBob, let's do-si-do
我好忧郁
I'm so blue
我也一样
I feel the same
没有礼物
No Christmas gifts
爸  太逊了
Dad, this is lame
大伙放心  不要害怕
Now, folks, don't worry, and don't you fear
圣诞礼物  马上送到
Your Christmas gifts will soon be here
但是你们有事要先做
But there is something you must do
否则圣诞老人就不来
Or old Saint Nick won't visit you
螃蟹鲸鱼  得先睡着
Good crabs and whales should be asleep
数羊入眠  才有礼物
No gifts unless you're counting sheep
互相致意  然后继续
So bow to your partner, go on ahead
砸昏自己  快快上床
Knock yourself out and go to bed
向左舞动  如蓝鸟飞
Now allemande left and fly like a bluebird
蓝迪奶奶去章鱼哥家
Randy and Granny to the house of Squidward
踮起脚尖  偷偷送礼
Walk on your tiptoes, give him his gift
别吵醒他  要快一点
Don't wake him up, now, better be swift
什么动静  我的老天
But what's that noise, holy mackerel
感觉这声音很不自然
Dagnabbit, that sound ain't natural
今晚肯定没办法安静
Sure ain't no silent night
竖笛噪音  吵吵闹闹
Squeaks and honks and clarinet squawks
塞圣诞袜  马上消停
Stop that noise with Christmas socks
接下来是  罗迪萝丝
Now, Rowdy's next and Rosie too
快快跳去派大星家中
To Patrick Star's we skip to my Lou
偷偷行动  别发声音
Now, sneak, sneak, don't make a squeak
礼物好大  漏出来了
That's a big old gift, and it's starting to leak
好多沙子
It's sand, sand
到处都是
Everywhere
来不及了  快上椅子
Too late now, better hop on a chair
这圣诞礼物非常离奇
This Christmas gift is mighty quirky
没事  派大星应该爱火鸡
That's okay, I think Pat likes turkey
小朋友们  干得漂亮
Come on, kids, you're doing fine
下一站是
The next stop is
来不及了
We're out of time
没办法把裤头村的礼物送完了
We'll never finish delivering
all these gifts to Bikini Bottom
珊迪阿姨
Aunt Sandy?
我们把你做的调配液带来了
We brought along that concoction you made
可能会有用吧
Maybe it'll help
行不通的
It ain't gonna work
圣诞欢乐已经快耗尽了
It's running short on Christmas cheer
我们可以补救
Well, we can fix that
对吧  家人们
right, family?
对
Yeah
圣诞节来得快  去得也很快
Christmas will come, and Christmas will go
我们互相表示爱意  那些日子最长久
What stays are the days that we say I love you so
万物闪闪发光
Everything's a-glowing
圣诞袜也满满当当
when your stocking's overflowing
树下就放着包好的圣诞礼物
And Santa's gifts are wrapped under the tree
我爱你们大家
I love you guys
对
Yes
有家人在一起  礼物变得多么美好
Gifts are so much better when your family is together
陆地海里都完全无所谓
Whether it's on land or in the sea
和你共度佳节  正合我意
A holiday with you is right for me
及时送完礼物了
We made it just in time
得跟圣诞老人报个喜
I have to tell Santa
圣诞老人
Santa
怎么
What the
这是个什么地方
Where am I?
我们拯救了圣诞节
We saved Christmas
其实我们是先毁了圣诞节
Well, actually, we ruined Christmas
不过我们之后又救回来了
But then we saved it
怎么回事
What happened?
快给我
Give me that
我就只记得先前有棵特别大的圣诞树
The last thing I remember was a big Christmas tree
然后你就摔了个屁股着地
Then you fell on your rumpumpumpum
还以为你没命了
We thought you was dead
不过你现在没事了
But you're fine now
我们还把你圣诞礼物都送完了
And we took care of your Christmas presents
所以我不在淘气坏孩子名单上了对吧
This means I'm off the naughty list, right?
你们修好了我雪橇
You fixed my sleigh
谢谢大家
Thank you, everyone
你们值得我圣诞老人送上特别大礼
You all deserve special presents from Santa
我找找
Let's see
这个怎么样
How's this?
我很感谢  圣诞老人
Appreciate it, Santa
不过今年圣诞想要的东西我已经有了
but I already got what I wanted for Christmas this year
我们并不需要高大上的玩意
We never needed nothing fancy
对啊
Yeah
谁还要什么礼物啊
Who needs presents, anyway?
咱就是说  我们很感谢能收到礼物
Well, we're, like, totally grateful for ours
你们咋知道是我们送的
How'd you know it was us?
礼物上面沾了点松鼠毛
Well, we found a little squirrel fur on our gifts
你们还整晚在房顶上唱约德尔调
You were also yodeling on our rooftops all night
虽然如此  还是要谢谢你们
But we all thank you nonetheless
不用谢我们
No need to thank us
重点在于  大家能欢聚一堂
What's important is that we're all together
不过我们还有这棵大树
But we also got this big old tree
这树可是珊迪给咱改造的
Sandy got it souped up for us
你们可以拿它当新家住
Figured y'all could use it as a new house
我们来了
Here we come
这才叫圣诞礼物嘛
Now, that is a Christmas present
虽然能见到你们是不错
Seeing y'all was great
但是免费东西最棒了
but nothing beats free stuff
来把这棵德克萨斯大小的树
Now, let's get this Texas-sized tree
物归原位  德克萨斯
back where it belongs, Texas
再见
Bye
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
以上就是一家疯狂松鼠
And that is the story of how a family of nutty squirrels
先是毁了  接着又拯救圣诞节
ruined and then saved Christmas
这么一个海底故事
down in the deep blue sea
没错
I know
我自己都难以置信
I hardly believe it myself
祝大家圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, y'all
欢迎大家回来
You all come back, now
听到了吧
You hear?
祝大家佳节愉快